{"data":[{"question":"When we got there they _____ for about an hour.","a":"were running","b":"had been running","c":"ran","d":"had run","answer":"2","explain":"\n- Past Perfect Continuous: \n+ Show that something started in the past and continued up until another time in the past ( They ran before and may continue running after we arrived) \n+ Structure: S+ had + been +V_ing ","category":"2","subcategorylv1":"15","subcategorylv2":"4","type":"1"},{"question":"When I met the general he _____ in command for six months.","a":"had had","b":"was","c":"had been","d":"had being","answer":"3","explain":"\n- Past Perfect Continuous: \n+ Show that something started in the past and continued up until another time in the past ( He was in command before and continued being there after I meet) \n+ Structure: S+ had + been +V_ing","category":"2","subcategorylv1":"15","subcategorylv2":"4","type":"1"},{"question":"The lonely boy _____ a girlfriend for a long time.","a":"had been wanting","b":"wanted","c":"was wanting","d":"wants","answer":"1","explain":"\n- Past Perfect Continuous: \n+ Show that something started in the past and continued up until another time in the past (He continued wanting) \n+ Structure: S+ had + been +V_ing","category":"2","subcategorylv1":"15","subcategorylv2":"4","type":"1"},{"question":"When she arrived, her boyfriend _____ for two hours.","a":"waited","b":"was waiting","c":"have waited","d":"had been waiting","answer":"4","explain":"\n- Past Perfect Continuous: \n+ Show that something started in the past and continued up until another time in the past (He waited before and still waited when she arrived) \n+ Structure: S+ had + been +V_ing","category":"2","subcategorylv1":"15","subcategorylv2":"4","type":"1"},{"question":"By the look of the place they _____ cards all night.","a":"were","b":"had been playing","c":"played","d":"were playing","answer":"2","explain":"\n- Past Perfect Continuous: \n+ Show that something started in the past and continued up until another time in the past (They kept playing) \n+ Structure: S+ had + been +V_ing ","category":"2","subcategorylv1":"15","subcategorylv2":"4","type":"1"},{"question":"Looking at him you could tell he _____ on the beach for hours.","a":"had been lying","b":"was lying","c":"had lain","d":"had laid","answer":"1","explain":"\n- Past Perfect Continuous before another action in the past is a good way to show cause and effect: \n- Lied on the beach too long- easy to recognize that he lied on beach (skin may be burnt....) \n+ Structure: S+ had + been +V_ing ","category":"2","subcategorylv1":"15","subcategorylv2":"4","type":"1"},{"question":"You could see that he _____ all day.","a":"has been smoking","b":"had smoked","c":"had been smoking","d":"was smoking","answer":"3","explain":"\n- Past Perfect Continuous before another action in the past is a good way to show cause and effect: \n- Smoked too much- easy to recognize that he smoked (cigarette ash..) \n+ Structure: S+ had + been +V_ing","category":"2","subcategorylv1":"15","subcategorylv2":"4","type":"1"},{"question":"When I arrived at the bus stop, some people _____ for half an hour.","a":"were waiting","b":"waited","c":"had waited","d":"had been waiting","answer":"4","explain":"\n- Past Perfect Continuous: \n+ Show that something started in the past and continued up until another time in the past ( They waited there before and may continue waiting after I arrived) \n+ Structure: S+ had + been +V_ing","category":"2","subcategorylv1":"15","subcategorylv2":"4","type":"1"},{"question":"He _____ the same job for 30 years when I was told to help him.","a":"was doing","b":"had been doing","c":"has been doing","d":"had done","answer":"2","explain":"\n- Past Perfect Continuous: \n+ Show that something started in the past and continued up until another time in the past (He did that job before and may continue doing it after I helped him) \n+ Structure: S+ had + been +V_ing","category":"2","subcategorylv1":"15","subcategorylv2":"4","type":"1"},{"question":"We _____ mountains for years when we had the accident.","a":"have been climbing","b":"climbed","c":"were climbing","d":"had been climbing","answer":"4","explain":"\n- Past Perfect Continuous: \n+ Show that something started in the past and continued up until another time in the past (He lived there before and may continue living there after the accident) \n+ Structure: S+ had + been +V_ing","category":"2","subcategorylv1":"15","subcategorylv2":"4","type":"1"}]}